Guide to the Laurence MacDaniels papers, [ca. 1915]-1986.
Laurence MacDaniels papers,
- Byan, P.M., Vice President 1956-6 North American Lily Society, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Correspondence between LHM and Byan
- Dr. Pfeiffer - Vice President 1956-6 North American Lily Society, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with Norma E. Pfeiffer
- Mrs. W.A. Rowell - Secretary 1956-7 North American Lily Society, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with Mrs. W.A. Rowell including minutes to 9th Annual Meeting 6 July 1956
- George Slate, Editor, North American Lily Society, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Correspondence - regarding North American Lily Society business 1955-7
- Stokes, E.F., Treasurer, North American Lily Society 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Committees - North American Lily Society 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Correspondence with various members of North American Lily Society in committee function
- Raymond B. Crawford, Publicity - 1955-6, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Jan de Graaff 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- 1956-57 North American Lily Society Directors, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Correspondence with F. Palmer, M.B. Ryckman, P.M. Byam, R.S. Pratt, L.N. Freimann, G.E. Holland
- S.L. Emsweller North American Lily Society 1956-, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- 1956-7 North American Lily Society - Hewett Seed Exchange, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Correspondence with H.I. Hewitt regarding seed exchange
- North American Lily Society - Foreign Relations - Alida Livingston 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Monumental Press - North American Lily Society - 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Correspondence with J. Ferguson regarding printing of North American Lily Society bulletins and yearbooks
- North American Lily Society - Members - Special 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Correspondence with A. Livingston and C.A. Best
- North American Lily Society - Members - General 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Lilies - General Inquiry, 1952-1956 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Correspondence 1952-56
- Lily Society - Boston Show 1955 12 July, 1955-07-12 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Correspondence with Arno Nehrling, Alida Livingston, Jan de Graaff; minutes of 1954 meeting
- North American Lily Society - 1955 - Sandy Best, 1953-1956 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Correspondence 1953-1956
- North American Lily Society - Business - 1955, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Correspondence with F.K. Hand of Canadian Pacific Express Company regarding shipment of books
- North American Lily Society Bulletin 1956-7, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Copy of President's message, notice of 1957 meeting and exhibit; seed lists; copies of quarterly bulletin; correspondence with H.I. Hewitt, C.E. Bullock, J. Ferguson of Monumental; miscellaneous notices; explanation of seed exchange; seed lists; list of donors
- Byan - Treasurer 1955-56 - North American Lily Society, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Correspondence including - quarterly statement of North American Lily Society July-December, 1955; list of life and honorary members, 3 blank checks (398-400)
- North American Lily Society - 1955 - Committees, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  Correspondence with various members; report of North American Lily Society Committee to Investigate the Registration of Lily Names; Awards and Standards Committee
- North American Lily Society - de Graaff, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 24)
- North American Lily Society - 1955-6 Directors - Freimann, Nehrling, Since Show, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Correspondence with above, including N.E. Pfeiffer, et al.
- North American Lily Society 1955 - Correspondence - Members - Special Livingston, Warner, de Graaff N.B., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Including S.L. Emsweller, Freimann; list of Certificates of Commendation of 1954; Nehrling, et al
- North American Lily Society - 1955-6 Monumental Press - John Ferguson, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- North American Lily Society - Dr. Norma Pfeiffer,Vice President 1956, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- North American Lily Society 1955-6 Secretary-Rowell, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- North American Lily Society - 1955-6 Yearbook - Report Orders, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  Including correspondence with Byam, and individuals who request copies, and Monumental Press
- North American Lily Society - 1955 - Members - General Correspondence, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- North American Lily Society - Bulletin November 1955, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  Notes for bulletin, Report of North American Lily Society Committee to Investigate Registration of Lily Names, etc.
- North American Lily Society Bulletin August 1955, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  Correspondence; notes; copy of pamphlet - Garden Lilies 1955; president's message notes; minutes of Final Business meeting 14 July '55, etc.
- North American Lily Society - H.D. Sayre Seed Exchange, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  Correspondence with H.D. Sayre regarding seed exchange 1956
- North American Lily Society J.C. Taylor - Awards and Standards, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  Correspondence with J.C. Taylor regarding awards and standards, including list of "Votes of Commendation" 1954; blank certificates
- North American Lily Society - Boston Show 1955, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  Printer's proof of catalogue for show; notes; correspondence with J.C. Taylor, S.L. Emsweller, Alida Livingston, Nehrling, G.L. Slate; memos and class lists
- North American Lily Society - Arno Nehrling - Prior to Boston Show 1955, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  Including correspondence with Neil Stuart, A. Livingston, and Rule Book for Exhibitors and Judges, 5th Edition 1947
- Suggestions on How to Organize and Conduct a Lily Show, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 38)
- 1954 Lily Show - Seattle, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  Including correspondence with Freimann, Byam, Taylor, S.L. Emsweller, J.H. Clarke, T.W. Beall, Archie Van Dorn, Fred Edmunds, Jr., regarding Seattle show
- North American Lily Society Cleveland Show 1952, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  Correspondence with J.C. Taylor
- Third Annual Lily Show - 1950 North American Lily Society, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  Copy, "NALS Exhibit Receives 1st Prize at NYS Fair"; Rule book for Judges and Exhibitors, 1947; correspondence with S.L. Emsweller, Isabella Preston, C. Yerex, J.C. Taylor, J. de Graaff, G.L. Slate, R. Rappleye, A. Nehrling, Inskip, E.F. Palmer, et al; newspaper clippings; pamphlets from previous shows; committee lists; floor plan of table arrangement, memos to members; notes, memo of infomation to Exhibitors, Secretary's report; copy-suggestions for Lily Schedule from G.L. Slate and L.H.M. 1950
- North American Lily Society - Judging Schedules - Older Material, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  Correspondence with Inskip, Nehrling, Emsweller, J.C. Taylor, et al; information sheets to exhibitors, etc. mostly for 1951-2
- North American Lily Society General Correspondence Current 1953-5, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  Including de Graaff, Byam, J.C. Taylor, A. Livingston, Sandy Best, C. Yerex, et al
- North American Lily Society - Miss Alida Livingston, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  Correspondence 1954-5 - regarding North American Lily Society Business
- S.L. Emsweller - North American Lily Society - Current, 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  Correspondence, 1950-55
- Seed Exchange North American Lily Society 1953-5, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  Correspondence with Sayre, Wardleigh
- North American Lily Society Bulletin June 1957, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  Including various bulletins not related to North American Lily Society; correspondence regarding Arnold Arboretum; Cornell Plant Bulletin 1957; notes [this seems to be a catch-all file for unfiled material], including nuts, Front of House business, postcards. At the end of folder: material pertaining to North American Lily Society 1957 bulletin
- North American Lily Society - 1956-7 - Answered not filed, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  Correspondence regarding Lily business
- North American Lily Society 1955 - 1956 Meeting, Mansfield, OH - R.C. Allen et al, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Family correspondence 1921, 1933, 1921-1933 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Family correspondence 1934, 1936-7, 1934-1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Family correspondence 1938-9, 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Business correspondence Oct. 1959-Mar. 1960, 1959-10-1960-03 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Business correspondence April 1, 1960-June 30, 1960, 1960-04-01-1960-06-30 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Business correspondence July 1960-Dec. 1960 and undated, 1960-07-1960-12 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Business correspondence January 1961-August 1962 and undated, 1961-01-1962-08 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Monthly reports regarding consulting work in Yugoslavia 1960, incomplete, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Final report (various drafts) on small fruit consulting 1962 and undated, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Final report (various drafts) on small fruit consulting 1962 and undated, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Translations of Yugoslavian newspapers, November 9, 1960 -May 1, 1962 (not complete), 1960-11-09-1962-05-01 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Summary translations of Yugoslavian agricultural newspapers, July, Sept. 1962, 1962-07-1962-09 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- (Manila envelope) Jugoslavia - walnut report and other reports, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 13)
- (Loose fool's cap sheets) 1. Talk - Saturday nightclub April 8, 1961; 2. Improvement of agriculture in Yugoslavia, 1961-04-08 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Variety lists - Orders from USA, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 15)
  Including correspondence shipping material to and from Yugoslavia
- Rosario, 1934-1939 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Business correspondence from Mexico 1934, 1936-39
- Rosario, 1934-1941 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  "Codigo Agrario" 1934; business correspondence 1934-1939, 1941
- No title, 1933-1943 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Business correspondence regarding Rosario 1933-43
- Rosario and Recent Personal, 1936-1943 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Correspondence 1936, 1939-43
- Rosario-Personal, 1934-1943 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  Correspondence 1934, 1939-43
- Rosario, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  1937 correspondence
- (Manila envelope) Rosario and Personal, 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  Consolidation accounts 1938-1941, Correspondence 1940-42
- July 1, 1937 - June 30, 1938, 1937-07-01-1938-06-30 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  Correspondence regarding Rosario including registration of various MacDaniel property in Mexico
- (Manila envelope) No title ( from "La Foto"), Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 24)
  Accounts, notes, "Dario Official' (various copies) maps
- (Manila envelope) Yugoslavia Translations 1962, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  Newspaper translations
- (Manila envelope) (In inter-campus mail), Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 26)
  Fr. C. Comar amd LHM translations of Yugoslavia Agricultural Newsletter
- Trip-travel Correspondence - Southeast Asia - Hong Kong, Japan, Alaska and Home, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  1958-9 - correspondence, shipping invoices, notes, itinerary
- Plant Introduction Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  Young and Other Than Philippines 1959-60
- L.H. MacDaniels - South East Asia - Plants Wanted - Older Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  Including paper by Paul Work - "The Role of Vegetables in the Tropics." 1957-59. Loose Oberlin Material - Newsletters - 1960-61
- Plant Introduction Since Return from Philippines Rodrigo etc., Valmayor, Kelley, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  Correspondence 1959-60
- Plant Introduction - Letters Since Return (see also I.C.A.), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  Correspondence 1959
- Plant Introduction - Current Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  See Other Folders for Answered Letters - South East Asia Trip Prior to Return to Ithaca 1958-9
- L.H. MacDaniels - 1912-, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  Oberlin material - notes from speech to Alumni luncheon to welcome Class of 1962
- Oberlin Commencement 1961, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  Reunion 1962
- (Grey envelope) Oberlin - Class 1912, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  50th Reunion 1962
- Oberlin - Alumni Association 1959-60, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  Class letters, correspondence, photos, newsletters, etc.
- IAC Current - New Contract 1961-62, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  Germann, Harrison and other Official see other folder (31) Monthly Reports - Fiscal, Contract
- (Manila envelope) Yugoslavia Correspondence 1962 Official, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  Outside Yugoslavia - Letter from J. Russell Smith
- Fluoridation 1962 Ready Reference Material, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Notes; form letter; pamphlets; Scrapbook with newspaper clippings regarding fluoridation issue. Poster on voting against fluoridation
- Fluoridation - Opinion and Propaganda, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Pamphlets, newspaper articles, etc.
- Fluoridation Material for Hearing 1964, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Notes, pamphlets, statistics sheets, etc.
- Fluoridation January 1966, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Open letter; draft letter to Reader's Digest, pamphlets, notes, etc.; Loose material: letters, newspaper clippings; copy of review by A. W. Laubengayer 4 October 1965, agenda of Common Council meeting 3 November 1965; letters; list of books and reviews - regarding fluoride; press release *WKO; letter from WHCU regarding speaker time on radio
- Fluoridation MacDaniels Letters, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Letters to various individuals, organizations, senators et al.
- Fluoridation - "Mottled Teeth", Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Articles and pamphlets on the dangers of fluoride especially condition of "mottled teeth"
- Foster: Letters and Mimeos, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 7)
  all fluoride
- Fluoridation - Clippings, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Fluoridation - Dupheates (?), Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Letters, petitions, articles, pamphlets, etc.
- Fluoridation - Costs - Damage to Pipes - Corrosion, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Letters, articles, notes; Loose material - 1963-65: letters, copy of testimony before Special Committee on Fluoridation of House of Representative Michigan State legislature 7 October 1963; pamphlets, articles
- Fluoridation Late 1966, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  newsletters, letters, pamphlets, articles, etc.
- L. H. MacDaniels, Fluoridation 1962 Source Material, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Newsletters; pamphlets; articles; copy of Proposal to Fluoridate the Ithaca Municipal Water Supply 27 March 1963; notes, letters, etc.; Loose material: delivery receipts from Post Office; copy of radio editorial WTKO; newsletters; newspaper clippings; letters; notes, pamphlets; etc.
- Fluoridation: 1965 Misc. Clippings, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Fluoridation: Letters to Editor - MacDaniels, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Letters to various magazines and publications 1962-63; Loose material - Fluoridation notes, letters, pamphlets, etc.
- Unmarked, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 15)
  Letters, clippings, etc.
- Letters Outside Comm. - Political and Personal Not Foster 1962-64, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  Loose material: letters, pamphlets, copy of minutes on Fluoridation Hearings 4 November 1964
- Fluoridation 1964-65 Miscellaneous Letters, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  Bound copy of statement to Common Council and Board of Public Works
- Fluoridation 1974 - Laubengayer Talk (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Fluoridation 1974 Older Material Relevant (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Fluoridation 1974 - Reference, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Fluoridation - Older Material Relevant (Envelope), Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Fluoridation - 1974 Selected Reference Older Material Relevant (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Fluoridation - Relevant Older Material (Envelope), Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Fluoridation - Mayor's Advisory Committee - Older Material (Envelope), Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Fluoridation 1974 - mimeos, etc. (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Fluoridation - 1974 Mimeos, McCay, Stare (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Fluoridation 1974, Letters, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Fluoridation 1974 Working Folder, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Fluoridation - Working Folder, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 29)
  Newsletters, clippings, pamphlets, etc. Loose material: miscellaneous Fluoride material
- Unmarked, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 30)
  Miscellaneous fluoridation material
- Fluoridation - 1974 Clippings and Manuscript (Envelope), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  Loose material miscellaneous fluoridation including letters and newsletters etc.
- Fluoridation, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 32)
  miscellaneous material
- Fluoridation - 1964-5, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Miscellaneous material including newspaper clippings, notes, editorial drafts, etc.
- "Not Filed", 1964-09-09 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  1st draft of Rotary Talk 9 Sept. 1964
- Pro-Fluoridation, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Including envelope containing material from Taber
- Source Material - mostly clippings - Syracuse (Envelope), Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Fluoridation - Alternatives, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 5)
  articles, newsletters, clippings, letters, etc.
- Fluoridation - U.S. Public Health, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Bound Paper: Fluoridation - Its Moral and Political Aspects. A New and Comprehensive Study, F. B. Exner, M.D.
- Post-Referendum Fluoride Clippings, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Fluoridation - Grand Rapids, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 8)
- 1965 Fluoridation Material, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Copy letter to Ithaca voters, copy of talk to conference of ICOF with Executive Committee of the Social Planning Committee of the United Fund; copy of open letter to citizens of Okanagan; articles, newsletters, clippings, etc.
- Fluoridation - Medical Miscellaneous Health, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Various articles, etc.
- Fluoridation - Miscellaneous Writing, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Various articles including statement by Frances C. MacDaniels 28 October 1965; miscellaneous loose material - including letters, pamphlets, etc.
- Fluoridation 1964 Reference Material, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Letters, editorials, press releases for radio, articles, etc.
- Fluoridation - Endorsements, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Miscellaneous loose material - including letters, notes, articles, newsletters, etc.
- Fluoridation - 1969 - Anderson, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  Notes, letters, (Ernest R. Anderson), etc.
- Fluoridation - Mayors - Citizen's Advisory Committee (envelope), 1967 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  Bound Copy - The Rational Case Against Fluoride Supplement 1967 by Elise Jerard; Miscellaneous loose material, including letters, newsletters, magazines, clippings, etc.
- Fluoridation 1967-68 - Jerard-Anderson, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  Letters, etc.
- Fluoridation January 1969, 1969-01 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  Letters, newsletters, pamphlets, etc.
- Pro-Fluoridation - Government Material (envelope), Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 18)
  Miscellaneous loose material
- Fluoridation - 1975 Campaign Material (envelope), 1975 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Answered Not Filed Summer 1970, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Correspondence: personal mostly; including copy of proposed article for North American Lily Society yearbook 1970, In Memory of Louis Melville Massey 1890-1969; tree crops correspondence including S. Chase, R. A. Jaynes; two photos: Tahiti and Philippines; open letter to DeWitt Park Improvement Committee; Black Walnut; newspaper clippings regarding fluoride and chloride dumping in Lake; scoring schedule, etc.
- Envelope: Unitarian Church Pulpit Committee and Other Church Affairs, Date Unknown (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, notes, printouts, etc.
- Envelope: Material from Dick Gilbert July 1970, 1970-07 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  2 fact sheets - Vietnam-Cambodia, newspaper clippings regarding Vietnam - mimeo from various publications regarding S. E. Asia; "The American Involvement in Vietnam" by George McT. Kahin - Cornell University 1970
- Current Letters - Not Filed 1970, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Including personal; Laubengayer (fluoride); G. Slate; local conservation issues; Northern Nut Growers Association (Spencer Chase, G. Slate, G. Weber, Wm. Clarke)
- To Be Answered or Considered June 1970, 1970-06 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Tree crops; American Horticultural Society - Ornamental Ratings Corn.; fluoridation; personal business; Northern Nut Growers Association (Jaynes) G. H. M. Lawrence; local conservation issues; bougainvillea; Black Walnut; treecrops; general nut culture; correspondence with Wayside
- Rosocea June 1970, 1970-06 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  notes (skin cancer?)
- Answered Not Filed 1969, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Newspaper clipping regarding Hook Place Park; F. S. Crysler of Cayuga Lake Preservation Assoc. Inc.; G. H. M. Lawrence; nut culture, Northern Nut Growers Association; N. A. Rockefeller regarding atomic power plant in New York State; name index of oral history (8-31-67); G. Slate; Jaynes; personal business; P. M. Synge = lily monograph 1969; Loose material: pamphlets; correspondence with USDA regarding fluoridation; Plantations, Nature Conservancy; 100th anniversary of L. H. Bailey - program; notes on polluted waters of U.S.; Cayuga Lake Preservation Association; North American Lily Society; personal; G. H. M. Lawrence; G. Slate; etc.
- Correspondence Current Not Filed - Answered January 1972, 1972-01 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Miscellaneous correspondence including fluoridation; personal, Yugoslavia personal; G. Slate; Oberlin, Northern Nut Growers Association; etc.
- Florida To Be Answered or Written 1972 Florida Current Unclassified 1971, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Miscellaneous correspondence while L.H.M. in Florida - including photo: aero photo negative of cottage on Cayuga and unmarked negative of tree branch; black walnut; Northern Nut Growers Association - Florida 1972; Material to Keep more miscellaneous material; Loose material (Florida 1976) including Men's Garden Club; general nut culture; personal; local conservation issues; personal business; Oberlin
- Florida 1974 Some to Answer, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Miscellaneous correspondence
- Florida 1974, 1968-1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Miscellaneous correspondence; Loose material: 1968-74 miscellaneous correspondence (some from Florida 1968- ) general nut culture; G. H. M. Lawrence; seed lists; black walnut; compost information; 1st draft manuscript Northern Nut Growers Association; 1st draft manuscript letter to editor - regarding Cayuga Lake; horticultural issues; Cayuga Lake Preservation Association; manuscripts regarding energy consumption, bougainvillea, etc.
- Correspondence April-May-June 1971, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Miscellaneous correspondence including personal and business; Loose material: 1967-71 miscellaneous correspondence including Northern Nut Growers Association; general nut culture; etc.
- Personal Correspondence 1967-68, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Including S. L. Emsweller; etc.
- George Slate - All Correspondence 1961-1966, 1961-1966 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Loose material: 1964-68 - miscellaneous correspondence
- Lily Society and Culture Nut Growers 1956-58, 1956-1958 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Correspondence including: E. F. Palmer; G. Slate; E. Stokes; Oregon Bulb Farms; price lists; international correspondence; S. L. Emsweller; P. Synge; Davey Trulo; some nut culture
- Florida 1957, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Loose material: glass negative and print; negatives and prints lilies, personal correspondence, coconut manuscript by McWhortor; biography of LHM; bibliography list LHM publications; correspondence with A.M.S. Pridham
- Florida 1971, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Florida 1969 Miscellaneous Letters, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Florida March 1971 Current Mail - Active, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- November-December 1970 - Miscellaneous Letters to Answer Attention, 1970-11-1970-12 (Box 13, Folder 20)